The Age of Stupid is a war, documentary, history
film directed by Franny Armstrong.
Pete Postlethwaite stars as a man living alone in the devastated future world of 2055, looking at old
footage from 2008 and asking: why didn’t we stop climate change when we had the chance?
The Archivist, played by Pete Postlethwaite.
The Age of Stupid is a 2009 British docufiction film directed by
Franny Armstrong, with first-time producer Lizzie Gillett.
The executive producer is John Battsek.
The film is a drama-documentary-animation hybrid.
It combines documentary footage from 2008 with Pete Postlethwaite portraying a man living alone in a devastated world of 2055, who asks "Why didn't we stop climate change when
we had the chance?"
The makers of The Age of Stupid were among the first to use the crowdfunding model and pioneered a new distribution system, Indie Screenings.
It premiered simultaneously on 62 screens across the UK in March 2009,
making it a record holder for the largest ever film premiere.
Critical reception was generally positive, with
reviews commending its message and format.
The film explores themes of post-apocalyptic
future, global warming, woman director.